Finding Aid for League of Women Voters of Grosse Pointe records, 1950-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
League of Women Voters of Grosse Pointe records 1950-2010
League of Women Voters of Grosse Pointe
2.3 linear feet (in 3 boxes)
2013057 Aa 2
Records of the League of Women Voters Grosse Pointe, Mich. chapter includes administrative, annual meetings and issues materials, and publications.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Material was donated by the League of Women Voters of Grosse Pointe (Donor no. 10902 ) in March 2013
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The League of Women Voters is a nonpartisan political organization encouraging the informed and active participation of citizens in government. It influences public policy through education and advocacy and not support or oppose any particular political party or candidate. The Grosse Pointe, Mich. chapter of the League of Women Voters was founded in 1950. Through the years the Grosse Pointe chapter has been involved in a number of social, civil, and environmental causes, such as juvenile delinquency, exceptional children (emotionally challenged children), voter education, voter services and rights, local government, libraries, parks, among others.
The administrative records of the League of Women Voters Grosse Pointe encompass material of the chapter's Board and include dated from the early 1950s to 2009. Also found here are versions and editions of by-laws, as well as awards and citations received by the chapter between the 1950s and 2009. Material of the chapter's annual meeting, called by the chapter "Local annual meeting," include meeting minutes between 1953 and 2009. Membership material, dated between 1950 and 2009, includes rosters and member directories. Chapter's many activities are reflected in the newsletter The Grosse Pointe Voter, or The Voter, and in a collection of material dedicated to specific issues. The collection includes issues of The Voter dated between 1958 and 2009. Also included is the chapter's annually published listing of Grosse Pointe's public and government officials, dated from 1960 to 2009.
Subjects:
League of Women Voters of Grosse Pointe.; Grosse Pointe (Mich.)--Politics and government.; Local government--Michigan--Grosse Pointe.; Voter registration--Michigan--Grosse Pointe.; Women--Michigan--Grosse Pointe--Societies and clubs.
- League of Women Voters of Grosse Pointe
  - Awards and honors, 1953-2009 (Box 1)
  - Board
    - Annual reports, 1957 1962/1963-1984/1985, 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Minutes of Board meetings, 1951-2009, 15 folders (Box 1)
    - Treasurer's annual reports, 1950s-2008/2009 with gaps, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - By-laws (Box 1)
  - Issues
    - Exceptional children, 1961-1966 (Box 1)
    - Fair housing, 1967, 1969, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Juvenile offenders, 1968-1969 (Box 1)
    - Local government control: Grosse Point Park, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Wayne County Home Government, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
    - Wayne County Home Rule, 1961-1968, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1977-2002 scattered years and undated (Box 1)
  - Local annual meeting, 1953-2009 with gaps, 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Membership, 1950-2009/2010 with gaps, 12 folders (Box 2)
  - Publications
    - Your Public Servants, 1960 Your Elected Officials, 1961-1977 with gaps (Box 2)
    - Your Government Officials, 1979-2009 with gaps (Box 2)
    - The Grosse Pointe Voter, 1958-1988, 14 folders (Box 2)
    - The Grosse Pointe Voter, 1989-2009, 10 folders (Box 3)